+1 416 846 0485 | TAYLAN@TAYLANPINCE.COM

WWW.TAYLANPINCE.COM

KNOWLEDGE

6 years of web development experience with **Python**, PHP, **PostgreSQL**, MySQL, **CSS**, **XHTML**, **JavaScript**, and ActionScript.

An excellent understanding of interface development techniques, browser quirks, semantic and accessible HTML.

Familiarity with web frameworks such as Django, CakePHP, Drupal.

A specialized interest in JavaScript and emerging libraries such as jQuery, MooTools and Prototype.

 $\label{lem:professional level knowledge of Flash and ActionScript 2 and 3.$

Advanced Linux user, capable of deploying and maintaining web applications on many distributions.

Ability to easily communicate with designers and respect their work in every detail, thanks to a background in **visual arts**.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Fine Arts Honours Degree (BFA Hon) Cross-Disciplinary Certificate in Digital Media York University, Toronto, Canada | 2002-2006

General Certificate of Secondary Education French Baccalaureate Diploma Lycée Galatasaray, Istanbul, Turkey | 1995-2002

EXPERIENCE

Interface Developer, Trapeze Media, Toronto | 2006-Present Interface design, CSS/XHTML development, ActionScript programming for clients such as Pizza Hut, Sobeys Paramount and CBS

Senior UI Developer, Navantis, Toronto | 2006 Interface design, CSS/XHTML development, ActionScript programming for clients such as Sirius Canada, MSN Canada, Microsoft and Fairmont Hotels

Web Developer, elmasepeti.com | 2005-2006 PHP, MySQL, AJAX development, online store system programmed from scratch according to user needs

Web Developer, turkmac.com | 2004-2006 PHP and MySQL development, Macintosh portal designed and programmed to offer a large number of services

Editorial Contributor, Macworld Turkey | 2000-2006 Monthly articles on PHP and web development

A complete portfolio can be found at www.taylanpince.com

ACHIEVEMENTS & EXHIBITIONS

Yearly placement on the Dean's Honour Roll | 2002-2006

Interactive Media Installation: Ghost, Gallery 1313, Toronto | 2005

Art Show: Inner Landscapes, AKASA Gallery, Toronto | 2004

LANGUAGES Turkish (Native) | English (Fluent) | French (Advanced)